Yellow Springs, OH 45387 | 937-371-1226 |

veldamart@gmail.com | https://github.com/veldamart/dreams |
https://codepen.io/veldamart/# | https://www.linkedin.com/in/veldamartin/

Professional Summary

Front End Web Developer who is knowledgeable in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, SQL and C#. A true team player offering over 5 years of experience in the software industry. Seeking the opportunity to provide outstanding, clean code in a collaborative environment.

Technology Summary

Transact SQL, Procedural Language SQL, C#.Net, XML, Windows Server, Bootstrap Framework, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and jQuery and Ajax

Professional Experience

Remote Front-End Web Developer, Dreams of Millions, Beavercreek, OH http://dreamsofmillionsinc.com/

June, 2011 - Present

- Programming tasks includes enhancements, maintenance and support for internal clients' applications
- Engineering software product changes, handling complex analysis and intricate programming to meet project requirements.
- Created web design for prominent Dreams of Millions, Inc., online presence.

.Net Developer, TEKsystems (ISSG, Inc.), Miamisburg, OH Focused: manufacturing.

Oct, 2015 - Oct, 2016

- Programmed in HTML, CSS, Telerik, and JavaScript to build Front end controls
- Designed scripts using C# and JavaScript in code behind to access the controls and objects, and queries
- Built code using lambda and LINQ functions to open Data layer to make calls to the data in the database
- Design new and used existing objects to open applications layers
- Asp.Net/ JavaScript/Html
- Coded JavaScript logic modal to render a Reject Scrap Pricing Report for ISSG client's in NUBC internal server
- HTML markup to Defective Material Report Web pages
- Developed asp server button controls to fire the send dmr event on the server side.
- Results: Improved quality and performance by enabling client to view reports without scrolling across screens
- PL/Sql Databases:
- New tables schema for MPS and NUBC Databases
- Created table scripts for web applications and reports. Results: improved performance for ISSG Clients
- Created unique table SEQ_Id on MAXVALUE 1E19 NOCHACIE START WITH 1 Results: created method to auto increment records on id.
- Granted database permissions to select, update, insert, delete on table to server on MPS_Code and Granted data permission on MPS_Code (Schema) to Principle. Results defined roles for user access to the data
- Created indexes to speed up scanning and sorting and selecting rows: Results reduce load on access records
- Created synonyms to database objects. Results: Secured the data in the database using alias for referencing objects in the database
- Coded Sql Script for Reject Sra Pricing procedure to query Data Warehouse for MPS and NUBC databases
 and designed code using for creating a new Reject Sra Pricing Report utilized Telerik UI controls. Results:
 Enabled Client to access replacement information on open records that were change and did not received
 a response.
- Imported Data to Oracle Database from Microsoft Excel spreadsheet application Results: populated database table with predefined data from client web application and reports.

Yellow Springs, OH 45387 | 937-371-1226 |

- Created package specifications that defined available resources for building web applications and reports
- Created the package body for implementation of every cursor and sub of every cursor declared in the package and those running outside the package. Results: Improves database performance by Built references to the data without altering the actual data in the database.
- Proxy handler services
- Designed web Proxies definitions, on the web client to communicate with MPS and NEMPS clients.
- Built Defective Materials Report proxy web definition
- Built the proxy call under the button click to the server to get the SendDMR object
- Web service
- Coded web services contracts to services for the server calls
- Server
- Built access to the sever for the Defective Material Maintenance Report Page
- Designed Interface [Service Contract] to directly call services on the Server side to enable communication to the data layer Built the Data Contract to implement the interface
- Coded the Business layer to set the rules, inherit the SendDMR object, and reference the data layer and Interface
- · Web Reports
- Developed Web Interface: Built custom classes to store data for a new Reject SRA Pricing web application
- Created Reject SRA Pricing Business logic to define the rules on how to access the objects in MPS and Nemps codes
- Built the Web data layer for Reject SR Pricing reports application by initiating the data and retrieving the data from the data object, also, setting custom properties to retrieve the data to return the custom objects to back to the dll file
- Coded Services and Added virtual directory and new service name by modifying Server Solution Service host in the App_Config file.
- Created the Reject Sra Pricing UI/Layer to interact with clients concerning reject scrap return information through accessing the web to filter the client search and export the output in a Telerik report, or extract into a comma separated file
- Other projects involved:
- Built new applications to generate pdf and send DMR pdf attachments through Microsoft outlook
- Developed application to extract in comma separate format and excel format
- Modifying html code and C# by adding new controls and features
- Built detail designs assumption documentation for application and database changes
- Built use case documents for testing applications and database change and functionalities
- Assisted new Team member on navigating through building reports and building query logic

Software Developer, Insight Global (Aero Fulfillment Services), Cincinnati, OH Dec, 2014 – Mar, 2015

- Ensured that bug reports were remedied and all issues were handled in a timely manner.
- Met with manager on a weekly basis to provide a detailed project report and milestone updates.
- Designed and developed reports in Crystal Server Reporting Services.
- Worked closely with clients to establish problem specifications and system designs.

Web Application Developer, Insight Global (Verizon Wireless), Cincinnati, OH Feb, 2014 – Nov, 2014

- Created a Visual Basic Shell script to send email notifications to user alerting them of open Issues in the Verizon Wireless System with critical time periods of 48 hours and those that were open longer than 30 days.
- Designed a data structure using hashtables, arraylists, and recorded selections to develop a pop-up window using Asp.net, JavaScript, and jQuery to allow users to update multiple devices from an Obout checkbox controls.
- Developed code using HTML, CSS3, JavaScript and jQuery to build asp.net forms and programmed the scripts in code behind using vb.net to enable users to edit devices.
- Created vbScript and batch File automation creating HTML table using elements and objects to send

Yellow Springs, OH 45387 937-371-1226 |

veldamart@gmail.com | https://github.com/veldamart/dreams |
https://codepen.io/veldamart/# | https://www.linkedin.com/in/veldamartin/

recipients email alerts using Microsoft outlook to notify internal clients of their past due open system transactions.

- Coded PL/SQL loader using VBScript to automatically move data from folders between SQL2012 and data warehouse servers.
- Use SVN subversion to maintain current and historical versions of testing the source code and web aspx.net pages.
 - Assigned new users Security Privileges and modifies current users Security Access
 - Communicated with internal resources on new system features and enhancements.
 - Improved existing web application used to test Verizon telephone numbers and devices:
 - Modified third party controls using JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax and VB.net and created new objects to
 enable users to select multiple selections and input data back to SQL Table. Used VB.net code to request
 an xml file to web service and return xml data back:
 - o Created service object
 - Created a request object for input for parameter
 - Created response object for parameter output
 - o Formatted input xml data
 - o Assigned the strdata to webservice request object
 - Called the sendxml file webmethod with the input parameters
 - Parsed the webservice response object to get the output xml data
 - Updated to XML tree structure that changes colors on an Obout Grid when a change event change event, no change in the data, or application failed
 - Created loading screen while page loads using JavaScript to display loading imagine while user waited for HTML page to load with the updates.

Programmer/ Developer, PDSI Tech/Technical Staffing (Techmetals Inc), Dayton, OH Sept, 2013 – Nov, 2013

- Enhanced server-side code in C sharp and Vb.Net 2010.
- Improved client-side code using JavaScript, and jQuery 1.7.1.
- Modified Publisher to create HTML 5, pages and added CSS 3 style to page.
- Modified .net page to add Tech metals metrics system to departments
- Designed new PVD web page and revised web pages for Tech metals Internet site at
- Improved Tech metals Standard Plating Specification web page at
- Use SQL to code queries of database tables with C# to upload data to their Intranet Web servers, 2005 and 2010 SQL Database Servers, and Internet sites.
- Debug and enhanced Visual Basic code for Techmetals Attendance Summary report.

Network Administrator duties:

- Created Tech metals new employee accounts working with Microsoft Exchange Server Moodle and Active Directory.
- Generated Microsoft Exchange Mail Accounts.
- Worked with Mail Traq Email Account to create mailboxes for new employees using SMTP.
- Worked with Active Directory to create Exchange Contact Techmetals DotNet.
- Using System Manager to add employee to Global Distribution and Security Groups.
- Developed folders for new employees on Techmetals Fileserver.

Yellow Springs, OH 45387 | 937-371-1226 |

Adjunct Information Technology, Brown Mackie College, Cincinnati, OH

Sept, 2011 - Sept, 2013

Instructor - Education Business Group

- Recorded lessons for online instruction.
- Maintained office hours to help students with questions and educational support.
- Developed and implemented lesson plans that covered all required topics.
- Selected appropriate materials to support student learning needs.
- Distributed course syllabus and answered student questions regarding standards, material, grading and progression.
- Tracked student assignments, attendance and test scores.
- Integrated technology into classroom instruction for a well-rounded and modern approach.
- Completed and submitted reports detailing course activities.
- Fostered students' commitment to lifelong learning by connecting course materials to broader themes and current events.
- Demonstrated a continued commitment to undergraduate teaching through full participation in the college community.
- Wrote course materials such as syllabi, homework assignments and handouts.
- Planned, evaluated and revised course content and course materials.

Courses Taught

Information Technology| Networking Fundamentals | Task Analysis and Project Management| A+ Certifications | Ergonomics and End User Support | Microsoft Office Suite 2013

Education

MS, Information Systems, Strayer University,
MA, Management, Antioch University McGregor,
BS, Information Technology, Wilberforce University,
AS, Computer Programming, RETS Technical Center